www.tvsubtitles.net
폴,에이프릴이요
Paul, it's April.
검사 결과 나왔어요.
I, uh, I got the test results.
마지막 상담 하려구요
I'd like to come in for one last session.
오늘 오후에 갈게요
I'll see you this afternoon.
에이프릴?
April?
폴,에이프릴이요
Paul, it's April.
검사 결과 나왔어요
I, uh, I got the test results.
마지막 상담 하려구요
I'd like to come in for one last session.
오늘 오후에 갈게요
I'll see you this afternoon.
02x32 April - Week Seven
In Treatment, S02E32
April: Week Seven
In Treatment 02x32 번역: 남가주(kagy@nate.com) 재배포금지
에이프릴 - 화요일, 오후 12:00
또 모자예요, 그렇죠?
It's the hat, isn't it?
멋져 보이는구나
Looks... looks nice.
우스꽝스럽잖아요
It looks ridiculous.
그래.. 네 메세지..
검사 결과 나왔다며?
So... so your message, you...
you, you got the results?
가려워 미치겠네
Well, it itches like crazy.
-그럼,벗어
-싫어요
- You can take it off if --
- No.
데니얼이 준거예요
- Daniel gave it to me.
- Oh.
-데니얼한테 얘기한 줄 몰랐는데..
-제가 아니예요,엄마가 말했죠
- I didn't realize that you told him about --
- I didn't. My mother did.
말하기 두려웠거든요
I was afraid to.
데니얼이 어떻게
나올지 두려워서?
Afraid of how he might react?
아무 반응하지 않을까
두려웠죠
I was afraid that he wouldn't react.
야구 통계자료 그런 거나 주절거리면서
날 피할까 두려웠어요
I was afraid he would walk away, rattling off
baseball statistics or something.
우리집 개가 죽었을때
데니얼은 알지도 못했어요
When our dog died, he didn't seem to notice.
그 개를 좋아했는데도요
And he loved that dog.
3달 후 쯤인가..데니얼은
'엑소시스트'의 여자애로 돌변해서
But then, like three months later,
he turned into the kid from "The Exorcist"
만나는 사람마다
너희들은 죽을거라고 했죠
and started telling everyone he met
that they were gonna die.
데니얼한테 말한 건
검사결과 나오기 전이니 후니?
Did you tell him before or
after the tests came back?
결과 나온 후예요
Right afterwards.
모두 왔어요
They came over.
어머닌 케잌 가져오시고
데니얼이 이 모자를 줬죠
My mother brought me a cake,
and Daniel gave me this hat.
내 생일 같았어요
It was like my birthday.
그럼, 축하할 게 있었다는 거니?
So, you're saying that you
have something to... to celebrate?
그럴만했죠
It's working.
척추뒤에 덩어리가
작아지고 있으니까요
The mass behind my spine is shrinking.
그럼, 예후가 좋다는 거네
So, that means: the prognosis is good.
네,그래요
Yes. Yeah.
와, 좋은 소식이네
Wow. That's great news.
마음이 놓이는구나
I'm just so... so relieved.
네 기분은 어떠니?
What do you feel?
모르겠어요
I don't know.
-몰라? 너 답지 않은데..
-네,이상해요
- You don't know? That's, that's not like you.
- Yeah, it's weird.
그사람들이 말해줄때
놀라지 않았어?
When they first told you, were you surprised?
그사람들을 믿었던 거니?
Did you, did you believe them?
여기 혼자 사세요?
Are you alone here?
-그래
-아이들은 없으세요?
- Yes.
- But don't you have children?
-아이들 있으시다면서요
-있어
- I mean, you told me you have children.
- I do.
어디 있는데요?
Where are they?
엄마랑 같이 살지
They... they live with their mother.
선생님도 신통치 않으시네요
심리치료사 시면서..
Hm... so you couldn't make it work either,
and you're a therapist.
그래서 심리치료사들이
사생활을 말하지 않는 건지도 모르지
Maybe this is why therapists
don't talk about their personal lives.
카일이 시에나랑 헤어졌어요
Kyle and Sienna broke up.
-언제?
-지난주인 것 같아요
- When?
- Last week, I guess.
카일이 저랑 저녁먹고
이 목걸이를 줬어요
He took me out to dinner,
and he gave me this necklace.
새 창사골 그런거요
줄은 실크고요
It's a wishbone or something,
on a silk chain.
깨트려서,깨졌을때
소원을 비는거죠
Which is apparently supposed to brake
and, when it does,
you're supposed to make a wish.
무슨 소원 빌건데?
And what are you gonna wish for?
2년 동안 데이트 했는데
목걸이 준 건 처음이예요
We went out for two years,
and he never gave me any jewelry.
왜 그 얘길 하는거지?
To what... what you make of that?
카일이 죄책감 느낀 것 같아요
I guess he feels guilty.
그럴 가능성 있지
That's a possibility.
아마도 걱정한다는 말 하려 했나봐요
자신을 표현하려고 하면서요
He'll probably tell me that he cares about me
and he's trying to express himself.
그럴 가능성도 있고
That's... that's another possibility.
너무 늦었어요
It's too late.
왜지?
Why?
전 죽었어요
I'm gone.
네말은..그러니까
카일에 대한 감정이 죽었다는 거지?
You mean... you're "gone" beyond an emotion?
걔가 사랑했던 여자
사랑한다고 생각하는 그 여자는..
I mean, the girl he loved,
the girl he thinks he loves...
더이상 존재하지 않아요
she doesn't exist any more.
머리가 다시 자라고
지금부터 회복 되더라도
Even if my hair grows back
and I go into remission,
내가 만나는 사람들한테...
from now on anybody that I meet, I'm...
-전 암에 걸렸다고 말해야 될지도 몰라요
-왜?
- I may have to tell them I had cancer.
- Why?
사실이니까요
Because it's true.
그래.. 암이 모든 걸 지웠다고
말하려는 거니?
So, are you saying that
your cancer has erased everything
과거의 일들과 예전의 자아는
사라졌다는거야?
that came before, that your old self
is just, is just gone?
카일과 마주보고 앉아 있었는데..
I was sitting across the table from Kyle...
카일 데리고 집에 갈 수 있다는 걸 알았어요
지금당장에라도, 머리털 없이도요
and I knew I could take him home with me,
even now, with no hair.
카일이 보고 싶지만..
I miss him.
카일이랑 잠자리를 하는 생각..
But the idea of getting into bed with him,
내가 옷을 벗고
내옆에 다가오게 하는 생각..
taking my clothes off and
letting him close to me, letting him...
역겨워요
다신 그러고 싶지 않아요
It's disgusting. I mean,
I don't want it, ever again.
그저 현재의 감정이야,에이프릴
변할 거다
This is just what you're feeling now, April.
That will change.
섹스 싫어하는
사람 있어요?
What kind of person doesn't want sex?
내말 아시죠?
You see what I'm saying?
-전 죽었어요,더 이상 없다고요
-넌 죽지 않았어,에이프릴
- I'm dead, I'm gone.
- You're not gone, April.
넌..넌 회복중이야
You, you are... you are recovering.
바로지금,극복할 힘은 가지고 있잖니
회복하는거 말이야
And you've only got enough strength for one
thing right now, and that's to get better.
맞아요
You're right.
-왜요?
-전엔 동의한 적 없었잖니
- What?
- Don't think I ever heard you say that before.
이별 선물이라고
생각하세요
Consider it a parting gift.
메세지에서 한 말을
그렇게 알려주는 거야?
Is that your way of reminding me
why you said in your message...
그럼,이번이 마지막이길
원하는 거야?
that you want this to be your last session?
네
Yes.
제발 더 받으라고
하지 마세요
And, please, don't try to convince me to stay.
일상에 대해 얘기를 하는 건
회복을 위해서도 중요한 거야
It's just that it's important for your recovery
to talk about everything else that's going on.
얘기하기 싫어요
I don't want to.
얘기하기 싫은 거 알지만
그게 네 패턴 이잖니? 애이프릴
I know you don't want to,
but isn't that your pattern, April?
-그만하세요
-그래서 우리가 상담해 온 거잖아
- Stop it.
- That's what we've been working on:
날 멀리하고 있어
your pushing me away.
-그냥 널 도울 수 있게 해주렴
-그럴 수 없어요
- Just let me help you.
- I can't!
아니,할 수 있어
Of course you can.
내가 하려는 건
너희 부모님들과 날을 잡아
What I want to do is,
I want to schedule some meetings
모시고 오는 거야
for your parents, bring them into therapy.
-데니얼을 데리고 올 수도 있고..
-그만하세요,싫다고 했잖아요
- Maybe we could bring in Daniel --
- Stop it! I said no!
-너희 어머니와 데니얼이..
-그만하세요! 지겨운 놈아!
- Your mother and Daniel --
- Stop it, you fucking asshole!
이제 괜찮은거야?
Is everything okay?
머리가 가려웠어요
I had to go scratch my head.
-죄송해요
-사과하지마라
- I'm sorry.
- No apologies.
왜 사과하면 안돼요?
내가 아파서요?
Why don't I have to apologize?
Is it because I'm sick?
네 상담사니까
Because I'm your therapist.
그래서요?
선생님은 인간 아니예요?
So what? You're not a human being?
누가 빌어먹을 지겨운 놈이라 했는데
상관없다는 거예요?
Someone calls you a "fucking asshole"
and you don't care?
내 기분은 신경쓸 필요없다고
우리가 처음 만난 날 말했잖니
I told you the day we met that I didn't want
you to be taking care of my feelings.
그럼 뭐하러 치료해요?
자기 중심적이 되라고 가르치시는 거예요?
What's the point of therapy, then?
Teaching people to be self-obsessed?
내가 그런쪽으로 도움이
필요하다고 생각하시는거예요?
Do you really think I need
more help in that department?
앉아 주겠니?
Do you wanna sit down?
네 일면이 상담 그만두고 싶기때문에
그렇게 행동한거 이해한다
I understand that maybe you reacted
because a part of you wants to leave,
하지만 네 다른 면은
이방에서 가치있는 일이
but maybe you reacted so strongly because,
일어나고 있단걸 깨닫고 있아서
격하게 반응한 것일 수 있단다
well, part of you wants to leave,
another part of you realizes
that something valuable is actually
happening in this room.
제가 완벽한 사람일 수 있고
I could be a perfect person.
열반에 도달했을 수도 있겠죠
I could reach nirvana.
내일 아침 일어났을때
가슴에 혹이 생길 지도 모르고요
And I could wake up tomorrow
with a lump in my breast.
-왜 상담 받아야 하는지 묻고 싶은거니?
-네
- So you're saying, "What's the point"?
- Yes.
왜 받아야 하는데요?
What's the point?
그냥 벗지 그러니?
Why don't you just take it off?
벗기 싫어요
I don't want to.
왜 벗기 싫은지
왜 데니얼이 이딴 모자 줬는지
And I don't wanna talk about why not or,
or why Daniel gave me the wrong hat
왜 대머리 보여주기
싫은지도 말하기 싫구요
or why I can't let you see me bald.
-이해한다
-아뇨,못하세요
- I understand.
- No, you don't.
네말이 맞아
You're right.
저 학교 자퇴했어요
I dropped out of school.
언제?
When?
지난주에요
Last week.
헝암치료 때문에?
Is it because of the chemo?
항암치료 거의 끝났잖아
너 졸업하고 싶은 거 아니었어?
But you're almost done.
Don't you want to graduate?
아쨌든, 직업으로 건축가
하지 않을거예요
I'm never gonna get a job
as an architect anyway.
-왜 그런 소릴하니?
-내 작품 보셨잖아요, 쓰레기예요
- Why do you say that?
- You saw my work. It's shit.
-그렇게 생각하지 않아
-더 이상 상관 없어요
- I don't agree with that.
- It doesn't matter any more.
많이 뒤쳐졌어요
따라잡는 건 불가능해요
I'm so far behind, you know,
there's no way I could catch up.
넌 그렇게 많은 시간
놓친건 아니야
Well, actually, you haven't missed
that much time at all.
학교가 널 봐줄거다
I'm sure the school would work with you.
날 위해 다닌게 아니예요
I wasn't even going for me.
엄마땜에 다녔던 거죠
I was going for my mother.
내가 대학 졸업하려고 하니
계획이 없어서 불안해 하셨거든요
She got so nervous when I was graduating
college because I didn't have a plan.
엄만 더 높은 학위를 원하셨어요
그래야 내 걱정 안하시죠
She wanted me to get an advanced degree
so she wouldn't have to worry about me...
왜냐면 내가 성공의 길로
들어서고 있다고 생각하시니까요
because I was on a "path to success".
엄만 입버릇처럼 말씀하셨죠
"엄만 데이얼이 조금이라도 행복하다면 행복하단다"
She used to say, "A mother is only
as happy as her least happy child."
그러시고는 데이얼을
보고 한숨 쉬셨어요
Then she would look over at Daniel and sigh.
전 속으로 생각 했어요
"저한테 하셔야죠"
And I would think,
"You're staring at the wrong kid, lady."
Well...
좋아,그럼..
얼마간 쉬지 그러니
Okay, let's, let's... let's say
that you did wanna take some time off.
그러는게 어떻겠니?
휴학말이야
Why wouldn't you just take,
like, a leave of absence?
다시 돌아가지
않을거예요
I won't go back.
그럼, 나때문에 지겨운게 아니구나
모든 일이 지겨운 거지
So, you're not just gotten tired of me,
you're actually gotten tired with everything.
어쩌라구요?
강의실에 가서
What am I supposed to do?
Go sit in a classroom,
교수 비위나 맞추며 친구랑
리탈린이나 삼키라고요?진심이세요?
[리탈린-주의력 장애치료 약물, 환각증상의 부작용]
suck up to my teachers?
Snort Ritalin with my friends, really?
저 암 걸렸어요
I have cancer.
23살인데
암 걸렸다고요
I'm 23 and I have cancer.
빌어먹을 그보다 뭐가
더 중요해죠?
How the fuck am I supposed to top that?
대체 여기 나가면
어디로 가야 되는 건데요?
Where the hell do I go from here?
에이프릴,어디든지 갈 수 있어
어디 갈건데?
April, if you could go anywhere you want
and anywhere at all, where would you go?
다시 돌아가려고요
Back.
-그러니까..집으로?
-네
- You mean, home?
- Yeah.
하지만 집떠난지 오래 됐고
너무 멀리 있다고 했잖아?
But isn't... isn't your home
so long ago and so far away?
그말을 기억하시는거예요?
You remember that?
주위에 유기농 농장
많이 있어요
There are these organic farms
all over the world.
일하면 공짜로
먹여주고 재워줘요
And they give you free room
and board for your labor.
그냥 이농장 저농장
옮겨 다니려고요
I was thinking about just
going from one to another.
얼마동안?
For how long?
몰라요
I don't know.
내 이름 잊어 버릴때까지요
Until I forget my own name.
기억상실증이 오지 않는 한
그럴 가능성은 매우 낮아
Well, unless you develop amnesia, the chances
of that happening are slim to none.
같이 항암치료 받는
여자애가 있었어요
There is a girl in chemo with me...
내 나이또래 였고..
um, she was about my age...
이름이 리릭이었어요
리릭 매리맨
Her name was Lyric. Lyric Merriman.
정말 아름다운
이름이었죠
That was such a beautiful name.
극복하지 못했구나?
She didn't make it?
네,죽었어요
No. She died.
안됐구나
Sorry.
마지막으로 봤을때 함께
나란히 앉아서 링거 맞았죠
Last time I saw her, we were sitting
side by side, attached to our drips.
뭘 적고 있는 것 같았어요
노트에다, 그냥 적고 있었죠
It looked like she was doodling
in her notebook, just doodling.
몸을 기울여 봤더니..
And so I leaned over, uh,
to look at it, and...
이름을 쓰고 있더라구요..
She was writing her name...
쓰고..또 쓰고..
over and over...
모두 다른 글씨체로..
그냥 자기 이름을요
in all different scripts... just her name.
아마도 잊혀지는게
무서웠나 보구나
Maybe she was afraid of being forgotten.
산 사람에겐 힘든 일이지
It's difficult to be the one who survives.
전 그러고 싶지 않아요
I don't want to.
살고 싶지 않다고?
Survive?
그냥 힘든거 같아요
Just... seems so hard.
사는게?
Living?
아프기 전에도 사는게
힘든것 같았니?
Did living seem hard before you got sick?
아뇨
No.
그 땐 길이 있었어요
There used to be this path...
좀..
가파르고..
and it was... like... it was steep,
힘들었지만..
밝았어요
it was tiring, but it was,
you know... well lit.
-더이상은 아니야?
-완전히 꺼졌어요
- It's not there any more?
- It's completely gone.
-제가 그런건가요?
-아니,그냥 길이 달라진거야
- Did I make it all up?
- No. You just got rerouted.
네 인생의 길이 변했던 거란다
네 허락 없이...
Your life's path has changed...
without your consent.
확실히 감당하기에
너무 힘들거야
It must be so hard to handle.
에이프릴
그렇게 느끼는게 정상이야
April, what you're feeling is normal.
그렇게 느끼는 게 당연하단다
It makes, it makes perfect sense.
하지만 넌 점점 성인이 될거야
But you are going to grow older...
다시 사랑도 하게 되고
원하면 아이를 가질 수도 있어
you're gonna fall in love again,
you're gonna have children if you want to.
그런 모험을 하게 되고
거기서 많은 기쁨을 알게 될거야
You'll have adventures, you'll know such joy.
선생님은 모르세요
저도 그거 모르구요
You don't know that, and I don't know that.
맞아 ,물론 우린 모르지만
가끔,아는 것처럼 행동해야 돼
No, no, no, of course we don't.
But sometimes, we just have to
act as if we do.
소용없을 거예요
It's not gonna work.
넌 최악의 상황은
극복한거야
Look, you've gone through the worst of it,
벌써 구멍에서 나오기 시작했어
아직 그걸 모르고 있을뿐이지
you've already started a climb
out of the hole, you can't see that yet.
괜찮아?
Are you okay?
인생내내 혼자일 것 같아요
I think I'm gonna be alone my whole life.
왜 그런 말을 하는거니?
Why would you say that?
그냥..느낌이..
예감 같은거요
That's just a... feeling I have,
like a... premonition.
다시 누굴 사랑하는
모습을 상상할 수 없어요
I can't imagine loving anyone ever again.
예전에 사랑을 어떻게
했는지도 모르겠구요
I don't know how I did it once.
정말 지친거 같아요
Looks exhausting.
내말 안다
I know what you mean.
전 암 걸린거고
선생님은 왜 그러신건데요?
I have cancer. What's your excuse?
난 더이상 23살이 아니라서..
I'm... no longer 23.
어젯밤에 다시
페이지에 가봤어요
I went on your page again last night.
내.. 뭐?
My -- my what?
홈페이지요
온라인..
Your page. You know, online,
선생님 상담에 대해
댓글을 남기는 곳이요
where people can comment
on you as a therapist.
그래,슬프고 텅빈
내 웹 도메인
Ah yes, my sad, empty, little web domain.
더 이상 텅비지 않았어요
So, it's not empty any more.
누가 글을 섰던데요
소피?
Someone wrote a comment,
someone named, uh, Sophie.
선생님 환자였나요?
Was she a patient of yours?
사실, 다른 환자
얘기 할 수 없단다
Actually, I, I can't, uh,
I can't discuss my other patients.
-저한테도요?
-그래
- Not even with me?
- No.
선생님께서 생명을
구해주셨다던데요
She says you saved her life.
홈페이지는 보셨어야죠
You should go look at the page.
많은 좋은 얘기
써 놨어요
She has a lot of nice things
to say about you.
대학다닌대요
행복해 보였어요
She's in college. She sounds happy.
그러마
Well, I will.
고맙구나
애기해 줘서
Thank you. Thanks for telling me.
제게 많은 도움이 되셨어요
You've really helped me.
에이프릴
난 별로 한게 없어
April, I, I really didn't do that much.
널 항암치료에 데려가고
네 어머니께 말씀드리기만 했지
I took you to chemo. I told your mother.
-나머지는 네가 한거야
-감사하단 말 하게 해주세요
- The rest, you did yourself.
- Let me thank you.
여기서 자신에 대한 책임감을 어떻게
받아드려야 하는지 알게 된게 중요한거란다
Yeah, but it's important that you see
how you took responsibility for yourself,
by coming to see me.
감사하단 말
하게 해주세요
Let me thank you.
그리고,상담 그만 받게 해 주시고요
And then let me leave.
너..확실한거야?
Are you... are you sure?
내말은..우린..이 방에서
대단히 많은 일을 해냈잖아
I mean, we have, we have accomplished
so much in this room.
두달전에 여기 왔을때랑 달라
You are not the same person
who came in here two months ago.
암 걸려서 왔고
지금도 암 걸렸는데요
Came in with cancer, I'm leaving with cancer.
그말이 아니란다
에이프릴
That's not what I'm talking about, April.
여기 왔을때 넌 매우 화 나 있었잖아
You were so angry when you got here.
-지금도 화 나는데요
-그래,하지만 지금은 그 얘기도 할 수 있잖니
- I'm still angry.
- Yeah, I know, but now you can talk about it.
처음 만났을때 무엇이 널
아프게 하는지 알지도 못했잖아
When I first met you, you couldn't
acknowledge that anything would hurt you.
지금도 모든게
절 아프게 하는데요
Now everything hurts me.
비가 절 아프게 해요
피부가 없는 것 같거든요
The rain hurts me.
I feel like I have no skin.
심리치료 용어로..
그건 좋은 일이란다
Well, therapeutically, that's...
that's a good thing.
넌 자신에 대해 많은 걸 알게 된거야
신뢰와 관용을..
I mean, you've learned so much
about yourself, about trust and acceptance,
항상 완벽해 질 필요가
없다는 것을...
about not needing to be perfect all the time.
그걸 지금
알기는 힘들거야
I mean, I know it's hard to see that now, but
자각의 좋은 점은 알게 됐지만
현재도 알고 있는 거란다
the great thing about self-knowledge is
that once you have it... you have it.
그런 자각을 이용할 수 밖에 없고..
And you can't help but put it into use.
알겠어요
Okay.
넌 아직도 네 앞에 많은 도전이 있어
그래서 누구랑 계속 대화해야 된다는 거야
You still have challenges ahead of you,
that's why I think
you really need to keep talking to somebody.
그럴게요, 선생님 말고요
Maybe... but not you.
선생님 일 수는 없어요
That can't be you.
내가 항암치료에 데려가서?
'Cause I'm the guy who took you to chemo?
제 생명을 살려준 분이라서요
You're the guy who saved my life.
다른 상담사 알려 줄까?
Do you want me to refer you
to an other therapist?
다음에요
Maybe later.
지금 말고요,지금은
그냥 쉼호흡 좀 하며 낫고 싶어요
Not now. Right now...
I just wanna breathe, and get well.
네가 그런 말을 하니
정말 기쁘구나
I'm so glad to hear you say that.
상담치료 없어도
사람은 살 수 있어요
People do survive without therapy.
그런 말을 듣는 건
나에게 좀 고역스럽지만..
It's very hard for me to hear that, but...
맞는 말 같구나
I guess you're right.
잠깐만 기다려 주겠니?
Can you hold on for a second?
이게 더 편할지 모르겠구나
This, uh... this might be
easier on your head, it's...
- 가죽으로 만든거야
- 예뻐요
- It's made of leather.
- It's beautiful.
내 아버지 거란다
It was my father's.
-그럼 선생님이 보관하셔야죠
-아니, 너 가져
- Then you should keep it.
- No. It's for you.
정말요?
Are you sure?
Hm-hmm.
-써봐도 돼요?
-그럼
- Can I try it on?
- Sure.
됐어요
Okay.
Wow.
우리 엄마가 좋아 하실 거예요
Oh, my mom's gonna love this.
애밀리아 에어하트 룩을
정말 좋아하시거든요
She really rocks the whole
Amelia Earheart look.
실크 스카프와 가죽 재킷
그런 거요
Silk scarfs and leather jackets
are kind of her thing.
-쿠바 스타일을 좋아하시는 줄 알았는데
-복잡하신 분이예요
- I thought Cuba was her thing.
- Well, she's complicated.
-모든게 흑과 백은 아니네요
- 그말 기억해두마
- Not everything's black and white, Paul.
- I'll try to remember that.
고마워요
Thank you.
- 안녕히 계세요
- 잘 가
- Goodbye.